<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Game design on Deployments and disasters</title><link>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/</link><description>Recent content in Game design on Deployments and disasters</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 20:18:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Improve</title><link>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/improve/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 21:29:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/improve/</guid><description>Motivation In order to facilitate the other two key goals of scaling and cooperation the Deployments and disasters rules gamify actual process of resolving the incident. This means that players don&amp;rsquo;t experience using the tools and performing the management actions directly. Rather they explain their actions and intent, throw dice and disaster master determines the outcome.
Despite not featuring concrete tools directly, this format is a good way to promote certain tools.</description></item><item><title>Cooperate</title><link>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/cooperate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 21:29:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/cooperate/</guid><description>Motivation Incident management process involves people from various roles. Those may include developers, ops engineers, support personnel, dedicated site reliability engineers, database administrators, etc. In order for incident to be resolved efficiently they may all need to work together.
In addition to coming from different backgrounds and being used to working in different conditions those roles also have different goals. For example support staff may be trying to send some kind of notice to clients that are suffering degraded performance.</description></item><item><title>Scale</title><link>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/scale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 21:23:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/scale/</guid><description>Motivation Deployments and disasters is a tool for educating medium to large engineering teams about incident management techniques and procedures. Its usefulness grows with the size of the team. For example, in a 5 person team a new procedure will be communicated easily and all team members will be on board with it quickly. Contrast that with a 100+ people engineering division. At that scale communicating the existence, let alone the details of, a new procedure becomes challenging.</description></item><item><title>Goals</title><link>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/goals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 21:03:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://antolius.github.io/deployments-and-disasters/design/goals/</guid><description>Key goals There are 3 key design goals that influence all decisions in Deployments and Disasters design. Those are:
Game should be scalable. Game should teach players to cooperate. Game should inspire players to improve. There are individual sections dedicated to each of the goals. There you can find more detail explanation of each goal and motivation behind it.
Impact of goals Some sections of rules, provided scenarios or other peaces of content on this site will call back to a design goal they reinforce.</description></item></channel></rss>